Hello English learners, welcome back. We are here at EnglishPod. I am joined with Erica.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回来。我们在EnglishPod。我和Erica一起在这里。
And my partner in crime, Marco.
还有我的搭档，Marco。
Alright, so today we're going to be talking about a really great topic, one of my favorites.
好的，今天我们要聊一个很棒的话题，也是我最喜欢的之一。
Beer.
啤酒。
Beer. So beer is a very popular drink, especially in bars and when you go out.
啤酒。啤酒是一种非常受欢迎的饮品，尤其是在酒吧和外出时。
Yes, it's very common with students, I think.
是的，我觉得在学生中很常见。
Yes, and it's also not very strong like a vodka or whiskey.
是的，而且它不像伏特加或威士忌那么烈。
Yes.
对。
Okay, so we are going to be at a bar today and we're going to be looking at some of this vocabulary that you would find.
好的，今天我们会在酒吧场景中，学习一些相关的词汇。
Yes, I mean you've got to know this beer vocabulary.
是的，你必须知道这些啤酒词汇。
Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and then we'll come back and look at these words.
好的，让我们先听一遍对话，然后再回来学习这些单词。
Hey man, what do you have on tap?
嘿，哥们，你们有什么生啤？
Heineken and Budweiser. We have a two for one happy hour special.
喜力和百威。我们有欢乐时光买一送一的特价活动。
Cool, give me a pint of Heineken and half a pint of Bud.
酷，给我一品脱喜力和半品脱百威。
Okay. Pint of Heineken, half pint of Bud for table six. What about some appetizers?
好的。一品脱喜力，半品脱百威，六号桌。要不要来点开胃菜？
Sure, let's have some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
当然，来点玉米片和马苏里拉奶酪条。
Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
好的，一共80美元。
What?
什么？
Well, it's pretty expensive for two beers and some food.
嗯，两杯啤酒和一些食物这么贵。
Yes, well, it happens sometimes you go to these very exclusive bars and they charge you like if it was gold.
是的，有时候你去那些高档酒吧，他们收费就像卖金子一样。
I mean, that's crazy.
我是说，这太疯狂了。
Well, let's take a look at some of these great words that we saw in Language Takeaway.
好的，让我们看看语言要点中的一些好词。
Our first word is on tap.
我们的第一个词是“on tap”。
On tap.
On tap。
So he asked, what do you have on tap? Now, this is a strange sentence. What exactly does it mean?
所以他问：“你们有什么生啤？”这句话有点奇怪。到底是什么意思？
Okay, well, he's asking about what beers the bar has.
好的，他是在问酒吧有什么啤酒。
But not in a bottle or not in a can, right?
但不是瓶装或罐装的，对吧？
Right. So, you know, in a bar, there's often this machine, right?
对。你知道，酒吧里通常有这种机器，对吧？
That will pour a very fresh beer, right, directly into the glass.
它会倒出非常新鲜的啤酒，直接倒进杯子里。
Into the glass. Yeah, this is a very popular thing because like you say, it's fresh beer.
倒进杯子里。是的，这很受欢迎，因为就像你说的，是新鲜啤酒。
Yeah, it tastes better.
是的，味道更好。
Tastes better.
味道更好。
Yeah.
对。
Okay, so what do you have on tap?
好的，所以“你们有什么生啤？”
What do you have on tap?
你们有什么生啤？
All right, let's take a look at our second word. Happy hour.
好的，我们来看第二个词：“欢乐时光”。
Now, this is very common and popular with bars.
这在酒吧里非常常见和流行。
Yes.
是的。
What is it when they have a happy hour?
什么是欢乐时光？
Okay, a happy hour is a period of time where the drinks are very cheap.
好的，欢乐时光是一段时间，期间饮品非常便宜。
Okay, so happy hour could be from 5 p.m. till 10 p.m., 50% off.
好的，所以欢乐时光可能是从下午5点到晚上10点，打五折。
If the drink is $4, then it is now $2 in happy hour.
如果饮品是4美元，那么在欢乐时光就是2美元。
Okay, perfect. And this brings us to our third word, a special.
好的，完美。这引出了我们的第三个词：“特价”。
A special.
特价。
So, this is a noun and what does it mean when a restaurant or a bar has a special?
所以，这是一个名词。当餐厅或酒吧有特价时，是什么意思？
It's like they're having a sale.
就像他们在搞促销。
A sale.
促销。
So, things are cheaper.
所以东西更便宜。
So, it could be, for example, a Monday night special.
比如，可能是周一晚上的特价。
Or like in the dialogue, a happy hour special.
或者像对话中的欢乐时光特价。
Okay, so it is a promotion.
好的，所以是一种促销活动。
Yes.
是的。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
And now, they ordered a pint of Heineken and half a pint of Budweiser.
现在，他们点了一品脱喜力和半品脱百威。
Pint.
品脱。
This is a very, very special beer word.
这是一个非常特别的啤酒词汇。
So, a pint is the size of your glass.
品脱是你的杯子大小。
Okay, so we understand how much a pint is.
好的，所以我们知道一品脱是多少。
What would be the equivalent in liters?
相当于多少升？
A pint is 0.4 liters.
一品脱是0.4升。
Okay, so almost half a liter is one pint.
好的，所以差不多半升就是一品脱。
Yes.
是的。
Okay, it is very common when you go into a bar, you can order a pint of beer.
好的，去酒吧时很常见，你可以点一品脱啤酒。
Yes, exactly. In English, we don't say, I'll have half a liter of beer.
是的，没错。在英语中，我们不会说“我要半升啤酒”。
Right, right. So, let's take a look at our next word on Language Takeaway.
对，对。好的，我们来看语言要点中的下一个词。
Appetizers.
开胃菜。
Okay, so what is an appetizer?
好的，什么是开胃菜？
Well, it is food you eat before your dinner or before your lunch.
嗯，是在晚餐或午餐前吃的食物。
Okay, so it's usually maybe like a salad.
好的，所以通常可能是沙拉。
Or a soup or something small that you can eat right before your big meal.
或者汤，或者一些在主餐前吃的小东西。
Okay, so some common appetizers at a bar and we saw them in our dialogue.
好的，酒吧里常见的开胃菜，我们在对话中看到了。
Nachos and mozzarella sticks.
玉米片和马苏里拉奶酪条。
Nachos.
玉米片。
So, nachos are little chips, right?
所以，玉米片是小脆片，对吧？
Yeah, corn chips and it has cheese and maybe some tomatoes and maybe some beans.
是的，玉米片，上面有奶酪，可能还有番茄和豆子。
Okay, so those are nachos. They are very common in the United States.
好的，那就是玉米片。在美国很常见。
Yes, yeah.
是的，对。
And what about mozzarella sticks?
那马苏里拉奶酪条呢？
Mozzarella sticks, a travesty on the world and humanity and everyone's arteries.
马苏里拉奶酪条，对世界、人类和每个人的动脉来说都是灾难。
Well, mozzarella is a cheese, right?
嗯，马苏里拉是一种奶酪，对吧？
Mozzarella cheese and this cheese is, what is it, how is it prepared?
马苏里拉奶酪，这种奶酪是怎么准备的？
You put it in some bread crumbs and then you fry it in oil. You deep fry it.
你把它裹上面包屑，然后在油里炸。深炸。
And you don't like this?
你不喜欢这个？
No, this is terrible.
不，这太糟糕了。
Why? They are so good.
为什么？它们很好吃啊。
Oh, my God.
哦，天哪。
Because then you can dip it in a little sauce and it's delicious.
因为你可以蘸点酱，很美味。
Marco, there are so many reasons why this is wrong.
Marco，有很多理由说明这不对。
All right, well, mozzarella sticks, a very popular bar food.
好的，嗯，马苏里拉奶酪条，一种很受欢迎的酒吧食物。
All right, well, why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be able to hear these words in context at a slower speed.
好的，我们为什么不以较慢的速度再听一遍对话，这样我们就能在上下文中听到这些词。
Hey, man, what do you have on tap?
嘿，哥们，你们有什么生啤？
Heineken and Budweiser. We have a two for one happy hour special.
喜力和百威。我们有欢乐时光买一送一的特价活动。
Cool. Give me a pint of Heineken and half a pint of Bud.
酷。给我一品脱喜力和半品脱百威。
Okay. Pint of Heineken, half pint of Bud for table six.
好的。一品脱喜力，半品脱百威，六号桌。
What about some appetizers?
要不要来点开胃菜？
Sure. Let's have some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
当然。来点玉米片和马苏里拉奶酪条。
Okay. That'll be 80 bucks.
好的。一共80美元。
What?
什么？
Okay, so we saw some really good vocabulary words there and now let's take a look at putting it together.
好的，我们看到了很多很好的词汇，现在让我们看看如何把它们组合起来。
Putting it together.
组合起来。
Well, in this lesson, we are going to look at one phrase that sometimes causes problems.
嗯，这节课我们要看一个有时会引起问题的短语。
So let's listen to this phrase that we're talking about.
所以让我们听听我们正在讨论的这个短语。
What about some appetizers?
要不要来点开胃菜？
Okay, so this phrase, what about?
好的，所以这个短语“what about”。
Yeah, I often hear people use it to ask a question.
是的，我经常听到人们用它来提问。
So a common mistake is asking, what about your weekend?
一个常见的错误是问：“你的周末怎么样？”
What about your new job?
“你的新工作怎么样？”
Now, this is incorrect, right?
现在，这是不正确的，对吧？
You cannot use the phrase, what about, to ask a question about information.
你不能用“what about”这个短语来询问信息。
So you, it cannot ask for information.
所以它不能用来询问信息。
Okay, because in our dialogue, the bartender said, and what about some appetizers?
好的，因为在我们的对话中，酒保说：“要不要来点开胃菜？”
Right, because he is making a suggestion.
对，因为他是在提建议。
Right, so he's saying, well, why don't you have some food?
对，所以他在说：“嗯，为什么不吃点东西呢？”
Yes, the phrase, what about, can be used to make a suggestion.
是的，“what about”这个短语可以用来提建议。
Okay, so I can say, what about going to the movies?
好的，所以我可以这样说：“去看电影怎么样？”
You know what, let's hear a few more examples of this, because I think it's really useful.
你知道吗，我们再听几个例子，因为我觉得这很有用。
Example one.
例子一。
What about these dirty clothes?
这些脏衣服怎么办？
You said you would wash them days ago.
你几天前就说要洗了。
Example two.
例子二。
What about going to the mall instead?
去商场怎么样？
I'm tired of going to the movies.
我厌倦了看电影。
Example three.
例子三。
What about a pizza instead of noodles?
吃披萨而不是面条怎么样？
Alright, so really good examples, and the same thing we can apply to how about.
好的，非常好的例子，同样我们可以用在“how about”上。
Exactly, so again, how about cannot ask for information.
没错，所以同样，“how about”不能用来询问信息。
Okay.
好的。
So you can't say, how about your boss?
所以你不能说：“你的老板怎么样？”
Alright, perfect.
好的，完美。
So let's listen to this dialogue one last time, and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about bars and beers.
所以让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来再聊聊酒吧和啤酒。
Hey man, what do you have on tap?
嘿，哥们，你们有什么生啤？
Heineken and Budweiser.
喜力和百威。
We have a two for one happy hour special.
我们有欢乐时光买一送一的特价活动。
Cool, give me a pint of Heineken and half a pint of Bud.
酷，给我一品脱喜力和半品脱百威。
Okay.
好的。
Pint of Heineken, half pint of Bud for table six.
一品脱喜力，半品脱百威，六号桌。
You want some appetizers?
你想要点开胃菜吗？
Sure, let's have some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
当然，来点玉米片和马苏里拉奶酪条。
Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
好的，一共80美元。
What?
什么？
Well Marco, I know you're a big fan of beer, and actually I think everyone here at Praxis is a big beer drinker.
嗯Marco，我知道你是个啤酒爱好者，而且我觉得这里每个人都很爱喝啤酒。
And this is the perfect opportunity to tell everyone about the world renowned beer shake.
这是个绝佳的机会，告诉大家世界闻名的啤酒奶昔。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
Okay, Marco.
好的，Marco。
Alright, so everyone that listens to this recipe is a non-believer.
好的，所有听到这个配方的人都是不信者。
They say that it is not possible for it to taste good.
他们说它不可能好喝。
Okay.
好的。
But here's the recipe.
但这是配方。
You take a liter of beer, or maybe half a liter.
你拿一升啤酒，或者半升。
So a pint.
所以是一品脱。
A pint or a pint and a half.
一品脱或一品脱半。
And you put it in the blender.
然后放进搅拌机里。
Okay.
好的。
Alright.
Now you take two eggs.
现在拿两个鸡蛋。
Okay, not cooked, not boiled, anything.
好的，不用煮，不用煮，什么都不用。
You take two eggs and put them in the blender.
拿两个鸡蛋放进搅拌机。
It could be one or two.
可以是一个或两个。
Okay.
好的。
And then you take about half a cup of sugar, put it in the blender.
然后拿大约半杯糖，放进搅拌机。
What?
什么？
And you mix all that together and you get this really good foamy delicious beer shake.
然后全部混合在一起，你就得到这种非常好喝、泡沫丰富的啤酒奶昔。
So a beer milkshake.
所以是啤酒奶昔。
Well, it has no milk.
嗯，它没有牛奶。
But it's actually really good.
但真的很好喝。
I've prepared it for some people who are like, no, that's not possible, it can't taste good.
我做过给一些人，他们说：“不，不可能，不会好喝的。”
And in the end, they're like, wow, this is actually pretty good.
最后，他们说：“哇，这还真不错。”
So did you invent this recipe?
所以是你发明了这个配方？
It's actually really common in Ecuador, in Peru.
其实在厄瓜多尔、秘鲁很常见。
I've even seen it in Chile, usually with a dark beer.
我甚至在智利见过，通常用黑啤。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
So like a Guinness or?
比如像健力士？
It could be a Guinness.
可以是健力士。
It's that a dark beer is a little bit sweeter, so you wouldn't add so much sugar.
黑啤稍微甜一点，所以不用加那么多糖。
But if you have another beer like a lager or a stout, you could still do it,
但如果你有其他啤酒，比如拉格或世涛，也可以做，
but just add a little bit more sugar because that beer is a little bit more bitter.
只是多加一点糖，因为那种啤酒更苦一点。
Okay.
好的。
Well, I am not going to try this recipe, but maybe you guys are.
嗯，我不会尝试这个配方，但也许你们会。
You should.
你应该试试。
Try it out and let me know how it works.
试试看，然后告诉我效果如何。
Yeah, you can tell us all about it on our website, englishpod.com.
是的，你可以在我们的网站englishpod.com上告诉我们。
Yeah, and we're definitely there to answer all your questions,
是的，我们肯定会在那里回答你们所有的问题，
and I'll be posting the recipe as well on the website.
我也会在网站上发布这个配方。
All right.
好的。
Well, we're out of time for today, but thanks for listening.
嗯，今天时间到了，但感谢收听。
And until next time, bye.
下次再见，拜拜。